HARISH NATARAJAN RAVI

UNIVERSITÄT PADERBORN | EMBEDDED & AUTONOMOUS SYSTEMS ENGINEER



Highly motivated and experienced software development engineer with a strong C/C++, Python, and Linux environment background. Expert in software development, and project collaboration. Flexible to relocate to align with project needs and career growth.

CONTACT

harrish.nr@gmail.com

+49 1759526201

Pahnhofstraße 13, 71229 Leonberg

Portfolio

GitHub

SKILLS

Programming

C/C++

Python Matlab/Simulink

Matiab/ Silliullik

Operating Systems

Linux

Windows

Software, Tools & Platforms ROS1/ROS2

Sensor Fusion

LiDARs & Cameras/SLAM

FPGA/Xilinx

Machine & Deep Learning

Git/Docker/Kubernetes

CI/CD pipeline

Testing and Debugging

AUTOSAR & ASPICE

Jetson Nano/Raspberry Pi

Data handling/analysis

Languages

English Native Speaker
Deutsch Intermediate

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Engineering

Oct 2020 - Sep 2024

V Universität Paderborn, Germany

B. Eng. in Electronics and

Communication Engineering

Sep 2011 - Jul 2015

♥ Visvesvaraya Technological University, India

PROJECTS & CERTIFICATES

- Self-Driving Cars Specialization
- Deep Learning Specialization
- Autonomous Vehicle Perception
- Visual Odometry for Motion Estimation
- Real Time Detection Transformers

WORK EXPERIENCE

ADAS Research Intern and Master Thesis

Porsche Engineering GmbH

Sep 2023 - Sep 2024

♥ Mönsheim, Germany

- Designed and implemented parking map reconstruction pipeline using SLAM.
- Developed LiDAR-based relocalization modules for generated parking map.
- Employed loop closure for parking map trajectory utilizing sensor data.
- Implemented methods for supporting HMI parking functions.
- Enhanced the performance of parking assist systems.

System Development - Video Perception

Robert Bosch GmbH

Mar 2023 - Aug 2023

Stuttgart, Germany

- Performed comprehensive analysis for L3 camera-based parking assist systems.
- Conducted verification and validation ensuring compliance with specifications.
- Collaborated with teams to ensure system reliability and performance.

Student Research Assistant

Fraunhofer IEM

Sep 2021 - Feb 2023

Paderborn, Germany

- Designed and implemented car-to-cloud demonstrator using simulators.
- Performed data extraction and analysis for telemetry data (SDV project).

Software Developer

Robert Bosch Engineering

And Business Solutions Pvt Ltd

math Apr 2017 - Sep 2020

P Bengaluru, India

- Developed service layer functionalities for the DCM package.
- Implemented functions for OBD modules to aid Application layer.
- Responsible for debugging and testing of OBD functional modules.
- Experience in Functional Safety, Diagnostics, ADAS/AD, and ECU Protocols.
- Worked closely with cross-functional team for platform release activities.

Technical Analyst

IBM India Pvt Ltd

🛗 Jul 2015 - Apr 2017

Bengaluru, India

- Implemented test automation scripts and worked on functional tasks.
- Performed server node migrations and cluster booting tasks without impact.

THESES AND RESEARCH WORK

Generation and Relocalization of Parking Maps

- Designed and implemented a parking map pipeline using SLAM algorithms.
- Reconstructed and Relocalized vehicle within the generated parking map.
- Evaluated the real-time performance of the pipeline in vehicle and simulation.
- Enhanced the performance of parking assist systems.

Disaster Response Robots

- Implemented LOAM pipeline to map and localise the environment.
- Enhanced the real-time performance of the pipeline using loop closure methods.
- Developed abstraction to plugin key points extraction and descriptor algorithms.

REFERENCES

- Prof. Dr. Erdal Kayacan <erdal.kayacan@upb.de>
- -Ing. Jing Gong <jing.gong@porsche-engineering.de>